(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T09:09:14.934977",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はーい！みなさん、ようこそ！
Hi everyone, welcome!
おめ丸ポルカ生誕祭2025！
Welcome to Omaru Polka's Birthday Stream 2025!
はーい！
Yes!
あ、ちょうどね、よかった。
Oh, by the way, perfect timing.
あ、こちらはハッシュタグになっております。
This is the hashtag right here!
おめ丸ポルカ生誕祭2025って、たくさんポストしてね！
Please post lots of tweets with it!
というわけで、えっとね、今日のライブテーマなんですけど、
So, today's live stream theme is...
おもちゃ箱みたいな感じをしています。
something like a toy box!
そして、タイトルは、
And the title...
パペットになっております！
is "PUPPET"!
これは、重要な伏線かも知れない。
This is an important hint!
もうね、最初からゲストといっぱい歌っちゃうので、もう今はね、もう何でもありの手を揉みようなんだ。
We'll be singing with guests right from the start, so right now, anything goes!
とにかく、えっと、後半にはすっごい重大発表が山ほどあるから、
And in the second half, there are tons of huge announcements!
最後までぜひぜひ見ててください！
Be sure to watch all the way to the end!
じゃあ、えっと、最初のゲスト、あ、姫を連れてきます。
So, for our first guest... Oh, I'll bring her in!
どうも！行ってきまーす！楽しみにしててねー！
See you there! Have fun watching!
半端なら K.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
So be it, if you're light-hearted
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show!
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me okay?
ほら Say No 低音響かせろ
Come on, Say No, now let's bring the bass!
なんだかんだってつまらないこともあるでしょう
Don't know what to say, things tend to get boring
ロンリー論理のノート ハンディ本気脱走
Lonely logic note, handy serious escape
やんなっちゃってどろに Bad ご法度だろうが
Can't take this anymore, it's bad, taboo
おぼれ墜ちて そろそろいっか
Drown and drop in mud, it's about time
もっと頑張って アガるまでもっと思いっきり頑張って
Let's work harder, let's work harder until I get excited
つながろうひとりよりふたり
Let's connect, two is better than one
増えたら安心 心配ないや
More the people, more I'm relieved
おれに任せてどんまい 波あり難題 みんなで乗っかっちゃえば
Alright let me do it, don't mind, if we all ride the waves of problems
案外さくっと行っちゃいそう
Perhaps it's easy to solve
半端なら K.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ 開演準備しちゃおうか
So be it, if you're light-hearted, let's get ready for the show!
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me okay?
ほら Say No 低音響かせろ
Come on, Say No, now let's bring the bass!
Yeah 今宵は暗転パーティ
Yeah, tonight's a party in the dark
Woah Woah Oh
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Dance, dance, sanitize loneliness, it's full house, thank you!
Woah Woah Oh
痛みまで おしゃれで
With pain, make it stylish,
ここでバイバイ Let go
Say goodbye right here, let go
どんな迷宮どうなったって 先行の化粧版で
No matter the labyrinth, what happened to it? On the leading cosmetic board,
卸込んで突っ込んで仕舞っちゃうでしょ Yeah
Unloading and thrusting it away, yeah!
Up and down なテンションで
With an up-and-down tension,
まっちゃっての相当
Getting way too crazy,
ドバっと吐き出すのは 本音のひとりごと
Spewing out all at once is a monologue of true feelings.
別に興味ない 特に何処に関係ない
I have no interest, and it has nothing to do with anywhere.
躱し込んでデパっちゃおうぜ Yeah
Dodging through and heading out, yeah!
合図を奏でて PrrPrrPrr ねえ Yeah
Playing the signal with PrrPrrPrr, hey yeah!
ほら集まって 夜行だ あー
Come on, gather around, it's a nocturnal prowl, ah—
泣いていこう
Let's go howling!
半端なら K.O.
Half-hearted means K.O.
踊りだせ 踊りだせ
Dance, dance!
孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Loneliness is sterilized, packed house of gratitude!
痛みまで おしゃれで
With pain, stylishly,
今宵も暗転パーティーだ
Tonight's another blackout party, too!
またのお越しをキドールウー
Waiting for your next visit, playing the doll—
次回まで お元気で
Until next time, stay well,
ここでバイバイ Let go
Say goodbye right here, let go!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
Okay たちまち 独壇場 Listen listen
Okay, instant one-man show, listen listen
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
歌舞け 振り切れ
Kabuki, shake it off!
ヤーーーショタイム
Yah-yah-yah-yah-yah, show time!
天辺の御成 ほらおいで
Behold the summit's grand arrival, come on over!
宵をコンプリート 本来ヘイヘイヘイヘイ
Complete the night, alright, hell yeah!
だんだんノリノリで 超簡単 ブラブラブラ パウ
Getting gradually pumped, super easy, brah brah brah, pow!
えも言われぬ Ain't nobody stop
Beyond words, ain't nobody stop!
全土絢爛豪華 Attention 騒ごうか
Splendid across the land, attention, let's make some noise!
意思表示にもう時期 衝撃の声高らか 堂々登板
Expressing purpose soon with a striking, high voice, stepping up boldly!
もう加減道は とっくとっくと
No more holding back, step by step,
Aye 絢爛桜花 御出馬した
Aye, splendid cherry blossoms made their grand entrance!
格好つけるつもりは NO NO
No intention of acting cool, no no!
オートマティックに溢れちゃう本能
Instincts overflowing automatically!
宣う断頭台の上で 焼け華麗
Gaily burning upon the proclaimed guillotine!
Da rat a tat a tat WARNING!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
万歳 遊ぶ気に言祝ぎ Shout it out, shout it out
Hooray, celebrate in a playful mood, shout it out, shout it out!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
はんなり 感情通りに八艘飛び Shout it out, shout it out
Elegantly leaping in accordance with emotions, shout it out, shout it out!
Hey oh 喰っちゃいな (hey ha)
Hey oh, eat it up (hey ha)
Rat-a-tat-tat-tat (Pull up)
Hey, uh, wa, wa, wa
満開総員 一気に飛びきり Jump around
Full bloom, everyone jump around all at once!
Look at me now 皮膚を破るそうに跳ねる心臓ぐらゐ
Look at me now, a heart pounding so hard it breaks through the skin,
激的事情 (Exotic vox)
A fiercely dramatic affair (Exotic vox)!
イニミニマニモ ご来場からのご光臨 隠れんぼしてるその気持ち解放
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe, presence upon arrival, setting free that hiding feeling!
(理性ディス) しゃかりきじみへおーて
(Dismissing reason) Getting frantic, hey!
蛇腹蛇刃 騙る二枚刃 野心家 嫉妬するようにジュース
Bellows blade, two-edged sword of deceit, juice like an ambitious, jealous person—
たぶらかすな かっとなっちちまうじゃ 余計に
Don't lead me astray, or I'll lose my temper!
蛇腹蛇刃 騙る二枚刃 野心家 嫉妬するようにジュース
Bellows blade, two-edged sword of deceit, juice like an ambitious, jealous person—
十色のバタフライ (No escape)
Butterfly of ten colors (No escape)!
ご存じの通り 騒々しい鼓動に
As you know, to the noisy heartbeat,
絆されても止まれない
Even captivated, we cannot stop!
衝動に塗装し描いた daybreak 肺貫通デイワン今日
Daybreak painted over with impulse, lungs pierced today!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
異例の危険度 比類なき活気充満
Unprecedented danger, matchless vitality filling the air!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
いちかばちか ああ
Make or break, ah—!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah Ready for my show
万歳 遊び気分にことぶき シャイナウ シャイナウ
Banzai! Playful celebration, shine out, shine out!
Shout it out, Shout it out
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah Ready for my show
万歳 巻き起こすために stay
Banzai! To stir up a storm, stay!
一切合切忘れて シャリンダウ
Forget everything completely and sharin' down!
Aye wah oh oh oh
右に左にまとめて バッタッタッタッタ
Gathering right and left, bat-ta-ta-ta-ta!
思いっきり キリ キリ Ciao Ciao Ciao
With all your might, kiri kiri, ciao, ciao, ciao!
何はともあれ ご唱和あれ
Anyway, let's all sing along together!
シャイナウ シャイナウ シャリナウ
Shine out, shine out, sharin' down!
記憶と現実の狭間で
In the gap between memory and reality,
彷徨い探した
I wandered and searched
君の居る世界
for the world you are in.
白い花を見つける度
Every time I find a white flower,
その姿を何度でも また思い出す
I recall your figure over and over again.
Forever glow
細い指先さえ
even your slender fingertips
愛しくて想いが溢れた
were so dear, and my feelings overflowed.
声はもう、届かないけど、でも
Though your voice can no longer reach me, but still,
心の絆は切れないと信じた
I believed that the bond of our hearts would not break.
果て無く続く様な世界で
In a world that seems to continue endlessly,
躓き方に暮れて行く日々も
even on days when I stumble and feel lost,
気付けば離れていたようでで
before I knew it, we seemed to be apart,
君と同じ道のりを きっと歩んでた
yet I'm sure I was walking the same path as you.
Forever snow
何故立ち止まったの?
why did you stop?
悔しさが滲んでいた
Regret was seeping through.
声出すの まだ遠くないから
It's not too late to speak up,
未来へ向かって諦めず走れと
run towards the future without giving up.
いつも胸に聴こえた
Always hearing in my heart
貴方の歌声
your singing voice—
憧れた強くて、でも 触れたら消えてしまいそうな姿
admired for its strength, but a figure that seems like it would disappear if touched,
追い求めて
I chased after it.
Forever glow
細い指先さえ
even your slender fingertips
愛しくて想いが溢れた
were so dear, and my feelings overflowed.
声はもう、届かないけど、でも
Though your voice can no longer reach me, but still,
いつしか運命が重なり合う
someday fate will overlap.
心の絆は切れないと信じた
I believed that the bond of our hearts would not break.
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams aren't something you just see, they're something you make come true!
輝きたい衝動に素直でいよう
Let's be honest with our impulse to shine!
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams are not just for dreaming, they are for coming true.
輝きたい衝動に素直でいよう スタートライン！
Let's be true to our desire to shine, Start Line!
もし君が立ち止まり 迷い日は 瞳閉じて ココロの声を聞いて
Should you ever stop and feel lost, close your eyes and listen to your heart.
「諦めない」その言葉が道になる
The words "never give up" will become your path.
あの日みた景色目指して進もう
Let's move forward toward the scenery we saw that day.
誰かの真似なんて 退屈だけさ
Copying someone else is just boring.
ひとりひとり 違うから奇跡 一緒に飛ぼう
Each of us is unique, making it a miracle, so let's fly together!
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams are not just for dreaming, they are for coming true.
輝きたい衝動に素直でいよう
Let's be true to our desire to shine!
後悔なんて絶対 君には似合わない
Regret is definitely not for you.
限りない情熱で 飛び越えていこう
Let's leap across with endless passion!
スタートライン！
Start Line!
さぁ 顔上げて
Now, look up!
チャンスが待ってる！
A chance is waiting!
微笑むペプラム うっとり水玉
Smiling peplum, mesmerizing polka dots.
見方を変えたらキュービック
Change your perspective and it's cubic.
新しい自分と 馴染みのアタシと
With a new self and my familiar self,
おしゃれのパレードは行く
the fashion parade goes on!
fashion check!
今日は姫カジかな？ (かな)
Today is princess-casual? (Maybe?)
カラーポップもいいな (いいな)
Color pop is also nice! (Nice!)
指に触れるカラフル イェイイェイイェイ
Colorful, touching my fingers, yeah, yeah, yeah!
キュンとワクワクさせるんだ
Making it flutter and thrill!
ピンクは夢見る自分に
Pink is for my daydreaming self,
ミドリはまっすぐな自分に
and green is for my straightforward self.
無限の遊び場にて
In this infinite playground,
万華鏡みたいに変われる
it can change like a kaleidoscope!
red, pink, blue, yellow!
例えばcuteに 例えばsweetに
For example, cute; for example, sweet.
いつものと違う日曜日
A Sunday different from usual.
夢から覚めても おとぎの国へと
Even if I wake from the dream, to the wonderland...
おしゃれの旅は続く
The stylish journey continues!
fashion check!
つま先で立って 星に手を のばした1日
Standing on tiptoe, reaching out my hands to the stars for a whole day.
翼の毛布にくるまって さぁ脚を休めて
Wrapped in feather blankets, let's rest our feet.
疲れているなんて感じない しあわせで
In such bliss, I don't feel tired at all.
瞳は花のように 閉じずに咲いている
My eyes are blooming like flowers without closing.
眠らなきゃ それなのに なんか夢ばかり冴えて
I need to sleep, yet somehow dreams overflow.
そうね 胸がおどるの 明日への幕があく
That's right, my heart is racing as the curtain rises on tomorrow.
明日への幕があく
The curtain opens toward tomorrow.
夜が明ける もうすぐ
Dawn is breaking, very soon.
頑張るための休息
A rest to help you do your best.
どれもひとつの準備
Each one is a preparation.
すごく大切なこと
A very important thing.
頬にそっとキスする
Giving a gentle kiss on the cheek.
おやすみ チュチュ・バレリーナ
Good night, ChuChu Ballerina.
こっちだよ！
Over here!
改めて、あ、どうもこちらに
Let's start over, ah hello, over here—
素晴らしい方々に来ていただきました！やったー！
We've had wonderful guests come join us! Yay!
みんな、いわまきちゃん？あ、ねえ、いわまきちゃんが
Everyone, Iwamaki-chan? Ah, hey, Iwamaki-chan—
せーの！お誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう！
Ready, set! Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！やばい！びちびち生簀にやられ……
Thank you so much! Oh no! I'm getting thrown in...
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！どうも！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much! Hello!
すごい可愛い！すごい可愛い子たちをね、絶対みんな知ってると思うんだけど
Super cute! I'm sure everyone knows these super cute girls, but...
まあ知らないとかほんとにもしかしたらまさか夢のような感じだけどいないと思うんだけど、もしいたらあれだからちょっと、えっと自己紹介なんか、あ、私おまるポルカと申します。
If you don't—though that's impossible in a dream—well, just in case, I am Omaru Polka.
ちょっと、じゃあ自己紹介をしていただいてもいいでしょうか？はーい！す、せ、先行きだからさせていただきます！
So, would you mind doing your self-introductions? Yes! We'll go ahead!
試合なる皆様へ、お元気ですか？
To everyone gathered here, how are you doing?
見える見える、スーパーアイドルになってる未来が見える！姫乃みえるです。よろしくお願いします！
I can see a future where I become a super idol! I'm Himeno Mieru. Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
はーい、まみめ、まみめむ、まみむめだよ！
Hii, I'm Mamimu Meh, Mamimu Meh!
あくまでも羊じゃないよ、アイドルだよ！よろしくお願いします！
I'm an idol, not a sheep! Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
パリパリ！パリー！今日も生まれ変わっていこう！アイドルの卵！
Crispy! Pari! Let's be reborn again today! An idol in the making,
わお！パリンだよ！よろしくお願いします！
Wao! Parin! Nice to meet you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はーい！みんなと一緒にショータイム！目指せ、きらめく瞬間を届けるアイドル、鈴代タイムだよ！
Hi everyone! Show time together with everyone! I'm Rindou Taimu!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
かわいい！かわいいっていう係の人。
So cute! The person in charge of saying "so cute."
改めまして、Vカツアカデミー配信部からようこそ！お願いします！お願いします！
Once again, welcome from the VKatsu Academy Broadcasting Department! Thank you!
えっと、メドレー歌いました！えっ、私が紹介していいんですか？え、なんか……
Um, we sang a medley! Eh, is it okay for me to introduce?
えーっと、まずスタートライン、そしてファッションチェック、そしてチュチュバレリーナを踊らせていただきました！
Um, first 'Start Line', then 'Fashion Check', and then 'ChuChu Ballerina'!
ちょ、慣れないからなんかすごい可愛いすぎてさ。
We're not used to this, so it's just super cute.
オーラがさ、こっちから来るじゃん。嬉しい。
The aura is coming right at us. So happy.
まず、あれだね、歌割とか一緒に考えたり。そう、楽しかったね、あれ。
First off, we thought about the song distribution together. Yeah, that was fun.
なんか、なんか歌詞っぽいからそこは君に……一緒に歌うから、ここあたり誰々にしようよみたいな感じで話すときがある。
Since the lyrics are poetic, we were like "Let's sing this part together, who should take it?"
気にしてみて、気にして？あの、お邪魔させていただけたらなと思っております。
Please mind it? We were hoping we could intrude.
ねえ、すごかったから、なんかさ、感じたよ、すごい。デミバスの素晴らしさを改めて！
Hey, it was amazing, so I really felt it. The greatness of Demibus all over again!
可愛い！うれしい！
Cute! So happy!
そう、あの、これからもぜひね、よろしくお願いしたいと思っております。よろしくお願いします！
Yeah, we'd love for you to keep supporting us. Thank you very much!
ステージでこうやって喋るだけでさ、ポルカ満足しちゃってるからさ。
Just talking like this on stage, Polka's already satisfied.
カフェになりたいな、ユリカになってお話ししてたいなっていうぐらいなんだから。
I wanna become a cafe, I wanna become Yurika and just chat away.
ゆか、ゆか、床になって！みえるも床になって！だめ！
Yurika, you become the floor too. Mieru, become the floor too! No!
じゃあ、天井になろうかな。じゃあ、正面になろうかな。
Then let's become the ceiling. Then let's become the front.
あと空いてるの、あと空いてるの、あと空いてるのなーい！
Are there any spots left? Any spots left? There're no spots left!
扉！
Door!
扉！扉！
Door! Door!
扉だ！
It's a door!
扉だ！扉だ！扉だ！扉開けます！
A door! A door! Opening the door!
はい、扉開けましたです。
Yep, I opened the door.
あのね、なんかさ、さっきさ、マイクさ持って練習してた時さ、なんかインタビューごっこして
You know, earlier when we were practicing with our mics, we were playing interview games...
インタビューごっこして
Playing interview games—
やばい、緊張ほぐすために。そう、でもなんかあれ
Oh no, to calm our nerves. Yeah, but like...
誰だっけ？お腹空いた？
Who was it again? 'Are you hungry?'
あ、あ、あそこ、水色の人？
Ah, ah, over there, the light blue one?
水色なの？水色なの？やばい！やばい！やばい！お腹空いた！
Light blue? Light blue? Oh no! Oh no! Oh no! I'm hungry!
やばい！終わっている！何に終わっているの？
Oh no! We're done for! What are we done for about?
お腹空いた！
I'm hungry!
自分の気持ちはどうでした？お腹空いた！
How was your feeling? I'm hungry!
ばらばりちゃった。あれ面白かった。
It fell apart. That was funny.
皆さんもお腹空いてますか？
Are you guys hungry too?
お腹空いた？空いてない！
Are you hungry? Not hungry!
空いてないの？ お腹いっぱいです。
Not hungry? My stomach is full.
お腹いっぱいなんだ。何か食べたんだ。
Your stomach is full? Did you eat something?
あ、実は なんか 食べなくて、食べなくて お腹いっぱいなんだけど
Actually... I didn't eat, I didn't eat, so my stomach is full—
こうやって初めて5人で踊れて嬉しさでお腹いっぱいです！
We're so happy to be able to dance together as five for the first time!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
そう、前は3人でさ、センターが変わって、4人になってさ、タイムちゃんが来てさ、
Yeah, before it was three people, then the center changed to four, and Time-chan came,
すごいなんか、その時も「もうめっちゃ！」って感じだったんだけど、
Back then it was like 'Whoa, amazing!',
「わあ、タイムちゃん来てくれたー！」って、今回はあの一般的なね、あのリスナーの感想で。
'Wow, Time-chan came!' And this time, it's just a general listener's reaction.
嬉しいね。そう、またね、新しいデミカツの良さが広がっていったなっていうところで、
I'm so glad. And newly, the appeal of Demikatsu has spread even further, so...
ぜひね、これからこれからも、あの宣伝部として頑張りたいから、
We really want to do our best as the PR department from now on too,
アイカツアカデミー宣伝部、1人で宣伝したいからさ。
Aikatsu Academy PR Department, because I want to promote it solo.
なので、ぜひね、あのチャンネルの宣伝とかももしあれば、
So if you have any channel promotions or anything,
今あのどんどんね、パパパパって。そうですね、私たちですね、4人でアイカツアカデミー配信部というチャンネルも持っておりますが、
Right now rapidly... Yes, we four also have a channel called Aikatsu Academy Streaming Department,
一応ね、ここでも個人でも配信のチャンネルを持っておりますので、
We also have individual streaming channels here too,
お名前とかでね、ごしゅばしゅばしゅばって検索していただいたりとか、あとXさんもやっておりますので、
So you can search our names, and we're also on X,
そちらの方で今日配信あるよとかもやっている感じで、
And we post things like 'There's a stream today' over there too,
ございますわよね？ です。
Right? Yes.
です。です。
Yes. Yes.
という感じです。で、えっと、そうですね。アイカツアカデミー配信部の方では、デミカツ通信というものを毎週土曜日の20時から生配信で、
That's how it is. And at Aikatsu Academy Streaming Department, we do a live broadcast called Demikatsu Tsushin every Saturday at 20:00,
この4人でね、お届けしています。 もしもしもしかして、もしかして？
Delivered by these four. Wait, could it be, could it be?
お前たちも？ お前たちも？
You guys too? You guys too?
え、お前たちも？おもろい。
Eh, you guys too? That's funny.
え、具体的には2月1日に予定します。
Eh, specifically, we have it planned for February 1st.
ありがとうございます。と、逆にね、こうやって遊びに行って、こうやってこっちに来てもらってっていう、姉妹校みたいなになってて、すごく嬉しいです。
Thanks, and conversely, visiting and having them come over, it's like sister schools, I'm so happy.
あの、最近本当にいろんなところでお顔を見かけてね、年末の去年のところから練習とか、なんかすごいいろんなコラボの幅が広がってて、あの、すごい一リスナーとしてもワクワクとしております。
Um, recently seeing your faces everywhere from the end of last year's practices and stuff, the range of collaborations has broadened so much, and as a listener, I'm super excited.
はい。みんな、要チェックだぞ！要チェックやで！頼むよ！
Yes. Everyone, check it out! Make sure to check it out! Count on you!
あ、あと俺は、あの、3月3月。
Ah, also I'm March, March.
あ、失礼しました。え、実はですね、こちらもアイカツアカデミー配信部のチャンネルの方で、3月29日にですね、大型無料単独オンラインライブをやりたいと思っておりますので、
Ah, excuse me. Actually, we also want to hold a large-scale free solo online live on March 29th on the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Department channel,
ぜひね、見に来てください。アイカツアカデミー配信部のYouTubeチャンネルでーす！
So please come watch it. On the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Department YouTube channel!
すごいぞ見える！めちゃめちゃ完璧だっぱぞ！さすがだ。うん。可愛い。
Amazing, I can see it! So perfect! As expected. Yup. Cute.
じゃあ、これからも一緒にいっぱい仲良くしてほしいというわけで、せずながらちょっと最后にもう1曲いいですか？もちろん！もちろん！本当にあれですよ、年末に出た新しいあの曲にちょっとお邪魔させていただいてもいいでしょうか？
Well then, we want you to get along with us a lot more from now on, so... even though we're doing it now, can we have one more song at the end? Of course! Of course! Really, can we intrude on that new song that came out at the end of the year?
いいでしょうか？わー！わー！それではじゃあ一緒に歌って踊りたいと思います！はい！
Is that good? Yay! Yay! Then let's sing and dance together! Yes!
行きますよ！聞いてください！HAPPY REFLECTION！
Here we go! Please listen! HAPPY REFLECTION!
咲き誇れ 未来
Blooming future,
トキメキは 響き合うよ
our excitement resonates together,
アイカツ アカデミー ！（ future ）
Aikatsu Academy! (future)
夢は恋に似てる
Dreams are like love
（始まりのコドウ）
(The heartbeat of beginnings)
走り出せば止まらないよ
Once we start running, there's no stopping
憧れた太陽 まっすぐに見つめる花
A flower gazing straight at the sun it yearns for
小さな祈り大きな願いになる
A small prayer becomes a huge wish
小さな祈り 大きな願いになる
A small prayer becomes a big wish
遠ざかる入道雲 追いかけて
Chasing away the receding cumulonimbus clouds,
雨上がりに
After the rain,
輝く
Shining,
笑顔を見つけた
I found a smile.
幸せ連鎖 1.2.3！
Happiness chain 1, 2, 3!
煌めく瞬間の 最大風速は今
The maximum wind speed of this sparkling moment is right now
反射する光は もっと強く
The reflected light shines even brighter,
ちから合わせて曇る
joining forces to clear away
空を晴らしていこう
the cloudy sky and make it clear.
迷いのない想いの連鎖
A chain of unwavering thoughts
磨かれていくよ
is being polished.
アイカツアカデミー！
Aikatsu Academy!
(We make Happy Happy Reflection Yeah)
虹色の迷路
Rainbow-colored maze
(可能性の回路)
(Circuit of possibilities)
落とし穴は怖いけれど
Even though pitfall traps are scary,
ワクワクしてる心を 連れていけば
if you take your excited heart along,
いつでもまた上を目指せるはずでしょう
you should always be able to aim higher once again.
今日も歌えること
Being able to sing again today
なんて奇跡！
is such a miracle!
とばしていこう
Let's soar forward,
輝く
Shining
空へ 音の階段登ってLet's GO！
to the sky, climbing the stairs of sound, Let's GO!
満開の笑顔で 繋げるメロディが好き
I love the melody connected with a full bloom of smiles.
反射する微笑み もっと大好き！
The reflected smile I love even more!
瞳にうつるものだけが
Only what is reflected in our eyes
世界じゃないと知った
we learned is not the whole world.
わたしらしく 感情を咲かそう
Let's make our emotions bloom in our own way,
根をはって生きてくの この場所で
putting down roots and living in this place.
背伸びして
Stretching our height,
打ちのめされ
getting beaten down,
立ち上がれば またへこんで 繰り返す
standing up, getting depressed again, and repeating it.
そんな毎日が最高なの
Such everyday life is the best!
刹那的
Fleeting moment
そのひらめき
That flash of inspiration
とびこむ勇気
Courage to dive in
明日を変えるため 進め
to change tomorrow, advance onward!
煌めく瞬間の 最大風速は今
The maximum wind speed of this sparkling moment is right now
反射する光は もっと強く
The reflected light shines even brighter,
ちから合わせて曇る
joining forces to clear away
空を晴らしていこう
the cloudy sky and make it clear.
迷いのない想いの連鎖
A chain of unwavering thoughts
磨かれていくよ
is being polished.
アイカツアカデミー！
Aikatsu Academy!
響き合うよ アイカツアカデミー！
Resonating together, Aikatsu Academy!
(We make Happy Happy Reflection Yeah)
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's shine, using our calling voices as a signal!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しにゆく スタートは何度だって
Parade, Parade, Parade! Going to search, the start is no matter how many times!
ただ 独り言を綴った
Just stringing together soliloquies,
ただ 始まりりたくて走った
just running because I wanted it to begin.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit up far away in the darkness,
遠く 暗がり に 灯った
それは 眩し過ぎた 名前
that was a name that shone too brightly.
それは 優し過ぎる 思い出 もっと
That was a memory far too kind, and yet
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず 結び合った
And unexpectedly, we became bound together.
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us".
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's shine bright.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along your frustrations and your love.
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
Our humble prayers are light, an endless omen.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can hold my head high for finding you.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
With premonitions still so uncertain,
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんて ないよ
let's sing—there's nothing to be ashamed of.
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary tale that no one can unravel,
いつか また逢える おまじない
a spell that ensures we'll meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
That story that began at zero on that day,
数え切れない 言の葉
countless words
数えるような 想いじゃないさ
aren't feelings that can simply be counted.
ほら 今 “僕等” を 一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" as one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える 刹那 夜は きらめく
In moments of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとなない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a sky like no other.
相応しい旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A journey fit for us is simply being by your side,
君と在ることなんだ
yes, it's about being here with you.
“ただいま” を聞けば “おかえり” って叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back."
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that just how it should be?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's shine bright.
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ！
What fills the darkness is you and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's shine bright.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along your frustrations and your love.
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき 兆し
Our humble prayers are light, an endless omen.
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in together with you is such a wonderful start.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Hello！ Hello！ everyone まもなく on stage
Hello! Hello! Everyone, on stage shortly.
ライライ口移し ワンジサ
Passing words along, one-two-three.
始めよう。「ようこそparty night」 誰かが語る 連日満員御礼 どうぞご贔屓に
Let's begin. "Welcome to the party night," someone says. Fully booked every day, thank you for your patronage.
「待ってたshow time」
"The showtime we've been waiting for."
誰かが語る どうでもいいような 顔を見せてよね
Someone speaks—show me a face like it doesn't even matter.
偶像捏造炎上 並べたなら一攫千金？
Fabricating idols and stirring controversy—if lined up, is it a fortune?
ふざけちゃいませんか？
Are you kidding me?
今辿り着いた 憧れの世界
The world of yearning I've finally reached
ここはまるで ペテン師の楽園
is just like a charlatan's paradise.
吐き気を飲み込む
Swallowing down the nausea,
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Dear sir, the onomatopoeia when the curtain opened
着飾る 人形は ピエロにくちづけを
Dressed-up dolls give a kiss to the pierrot.
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
Today's grand finale—the script laughs.
騙されてくれる 貴方達と
Together with all of you who let yourselves be deceived,
アタシ 今ここで 何をしてる？
what am I even doing here right now?
耳をつんざく 拍手喝采 サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
Ear-splitting applause and cheers—even a monkey can become human if flattered.
フォーカスされた 日常
A focused everyday life,
引き金を抱いて 心中するように
holding the trigger as if committing double suicide.
一回、二回、三回 嘘を重ねて
One, two, three times, piling up lies,
十回、千回、億回 瞳を逸して
ten, a thousand, a hundred million times, looking away.
あれ？なんだっけかな アタシは誰？
Huh? What was it again? Who am I?
もうウンザリした 仮面舞踏会
I'm already sick of this masquerade ball.
とりろとりのない ワルツでお迎え
Welcoming us with a monotonous waltz.
艶作の中 戯けてみせて 嘲ってみせてよ
Amidst the melodrama, act foolish and mock me.
アタシの世界は ぐるぐるクルクル ぐるぐる廻っていく
My world spins round and round, dizzying and swirling.
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Dear sir, the onomatopoeia when the curtain opened,
群がれる 人形は ダリアの花束を
gregarious dolls holding bouquets of dahlias.
選んでくれた服を着て 踊りましょう
Let's wear the clothes you chose and dance.
騙されてくれる 貴方達と
Together with all of you who let yourselves be deceived,
いいよ もうこれが 好きだっただけだろ？
Fine, isn't this just what you loved all along?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off the persona.
とっくに終わった 喜劇は 悲劇と化してなお
Even as the comedy that ended long ago turns into tragedy,
耳をつんざく 拍手喝采
ear-splitting applause and cheers,
猿もおだてればヒトにもなれる
even a monkey can become human if flattered.
君からのデータ解凍中 もう盗まれないように
Unfreezing data from you, so it won't be stolen again
君からの愛に回答中 好きって気持ちだけで
Replying to the love from you, just with the feeling of like
支えるってことなんだって
that it's about supporting,
もう思わなくていいよ
you don't have to think you can't do that anymore.
交換こLOVE....
Exchange this LOVE....
ペルソナ 君への好きがくれる顔
Persona, the face you give me when I like you
今まで知らなかった僕より僕なんなん?
What is it, more me than the me I never knew until now?
生まれたものは全部借りものさ
Everything born into this world is borrowed.
言葉も色も身体も
Words, colors, and body,
僕がじゃなく僕を作っている
shaping not "I" but "ME".
Oh! CRAZY LIFE MAKE U CHARMING
危機からの回避 凍結中 気持ちもうバレないように
Avoiding crisis, frozen, so my feelings won't be exposed again
かっこいいだけを見せるのが ダサいって美学なんて
The aesthetic of only showing your cool side is cheesy
邪魔だってわかってって
Even though I knew it was a hindrance,
捨てられなかった青春
youth that I couldn't throw away.
不器用をスクショしないで
Don't screenshot my clumsiness,
なんJ.V.I.P I’m gonna bounce
VIP lounge, I'm gonna bounce.
ペルソナ 嘘つきばかりだから
Persona, because everyone is a liar,
好きの技法 解説動画付きって
with love technique explanation videos,
親切丁寧信じちゃうな
I end up believing them, so kind and polite.
不甲斐ない深夜配信
Pathetic late-night livestream,
僕だけが視聴者だったいいな
I wish I was the only viewer.
キラキラ魔法は
The sparkling magic is
TWINKle TWINKle
目眩ませ
dazzling.
全幕幕が明けたその音の元で 群がる人形は
As the curtain rises to that sound, the swarming dolls
艶やかな裸体を選んで着飾って踊りましょう
choose their glamorous bodies, dress up, and dance.
騙されてくれるあなたたちと
With you who let yourselves be deceived,
いいよもう これが好きだったんだろう?
alright then, this is what you liked, right?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off your persona
とっくに終わった喜劇は
The comedy that ended long ago
悲劇と化してなお
has turned into a tragedy, yet
今日も普通に楽しかったよ
Today was normally fun, too.
さあ、刮目してくれよ
Now, open your eyes wide
本当の僕はアタシじゃないから
because the real me isn't "atashi".
今日も普通に楽しかったよ
Today was normally fun, too.
全幕幕が閉じたそのオノマトペ
The onomatopoeia of the final curtain closing
着せ替え人形と雛のアンコール
Dress-up dolls and hina dolls' encore
本日大団円 脚本が笑うどうしようもないよな!
Today is a grand finale, the script laughs—there's nothing we can do!
どこの誰でもいい 上喜に呑むなよと
No matter who it is, don't get too carried away in high spirits
せめて一回言ってくれ
At least say it to me once
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と気付けばそこには一人で
Realizing "there's no turning back," you're all alone there.
占う なう なう... 狂いな 泥人形
Fortune-telling, go crazy, mud doll
踊れ 踊れ 狂いな 泥人形
Dance, dance, go crazy, mud doll
予定調和の物語
The story of preordained harmony
というわけで!
And with that!
え、いつもおなじみのペルソナで、今、ここまで来ましたが、
um, with our usual "Persona", we've made it this far,
まず、ゲストたくさん来てくれて、ありがとうございます!
but first, thank you so much for having so many guests come!
なんかね、今回は本当にね、ここまで駆け抜けちゃったから
You know, this time we really rushed through all the way here,
ま、本当に、あの、デミカツの子たちも来てくれたし、
so really, um, Demikatsu's kids came too,
もうこちらとしてはもう、満腹満腹なのですが、
and from our side we're completely stuffed,
こちらで、ま、いつもおなじみここ、あのシャベリと言ったら、告知タイムがあります!グッズ告知今回も出ます!こちら!
but right here, as usual, speaking of chatting, we have announcement time! Goods announcements are coming out this time too! Right here!
尾丸ポルカ 誕生日記念2025
[Omaru Polka Birthday Anniversary 2025]
B2タペストリー「いらっしゃいませ、ようこそお客様!」
B2 Tapestry "Welcome, welcome, valued customer!"
続きとかも、あ、ポルカ、ただいまじゃないけど、
...and as for the rest, ah, Polka—well, not 'I'm home,' but
ホテルに来たよみたいな感じで見ていただければいいかなと思っております。
more like you've come to a hotel, I hope you enjoy it with that kind of vibe.
一瞬にしてお部屋がホテルに…
In an instant, your room turns into a hotel...
大代わりじゃねぇな。はい！
A replacement—no, not a replacement. Yep!
ええと、続きまして、2つ目、こちら！
Um, moving on to the second item, here it is!
はい！
Ta-da!
こちらですね、ドアプレート風ランダムアクリルキーホルダーになっております！
This is a doorplate-style random acrylic keychain!
全4種類からランダムに1種類が入っております。
Each contains one random out of all four types.
いや、これは夢のホテルのシチュエーションに描いていただきました！
Yes, it was drawn in a dream hotel scenario!
なんと、いろんなポルカがいるね。
There are so many different Polkas, right?
ええと、ホテルマンがコンセプトだったさっきのと続いて、ホテルの服着たやつと、メイドさんっぽいポルカと、お出かけのポルカと…
Um, continuing from the hotelman concept earlier, one in hotel attire, a maid-like Polka, an outing Polka, and...
はあ、あいつは死んでるな。もうだめみたいなポルカが入ってます。
Ah, that one looks dead. Like, 'I'm done for' Polka is in there.
はい、ええと、このもうだめみたいなポルカのTシャツがなんと、ええ、グッズになっております。
Yes, um, that 'I'm done for' Polka T-shirt has somehow become actual merchandise!
さあ、3つ目のグッズ、こちら！ポルカと一緒に低気圧と戦うTシャツ！
Now for the third item, here it is! The T-shirt to fight low pressure alongside Polka!
こちら、ポルカが書きました。はい！
Polka drew this one. Yep!
あの、低気圧オルカということでね、一緒にこれ着て、低気圧と抗ったり、低気圧に負けたりしましょう！
Um, as 'Low Pressure Polka,' let's wear this together and fight back against low pressure, or lose to it!
ポルカも着ます。一緒にね、着られたらいいなって思ってます！
Polka will wear it too. I hope we can wear it together!
というわけで、グッズ、もう1つ！
So, one more item!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
はい、ポルカの顔面ハンガー！
Yes, Polka's facial hanger!
いやね、来るとは思わんよ、顔面ハンガーのブーム。なんかポルカもさっきさ、スタジオでさ、こうやって一緒に着替えてる時にさ、もう置いちゃおっかなって思ったんだよね。
I didn't expect a facial hanger boom, you know. Earlier in the studio, when we were changing together, I thought, 'Should I just put it here?'
まあ、許すとはされるかかんないけれども、みんなもやっぱポルカの、こうTシャツも出したし、ポルカのハンガーも置いて、ちょっと飾っとくっていうのはどうでしょうか？
Well, I don't know if it's allowed or not, but how about putting out Polka's T-shirt and also Polka's hanger to decorate your room?
発表もたくさん出てることだし、いろんなねアパレルグッズなんかも最近は出てるので、いいんじゃないでしょうか？顔面ハンガー。2、3個ぐらい買っといてもいいと思います。
There are so many announcements, and various apparel goods have been coming out lately, so isn't it great? Facial hanger. I think you can buy two or three of them.
それではですね、最後にこちら！はい！
Now then, finally, here it is! Yes!
ずつ販売、単品でこちら、「どきどき♡ハラハラなホテルウェルカムボイス」！
Sold separately, individually, this is the 'Heart-pounding ♡ Thrilling Hotel Welcome Voice'!
なんかホテルとホテルをちょっとかけてるのかな、これ。うん。ちょっとポルカが名前つけたからちょっとわかんないです。
It's like a play on words with 'hotel' and 'hotel'... wait, since Polka named it, I'm not entirely sure.
あ、今回も全部ね、あの、ポルカが名前をつけているので、あ、センス、ポルカだなって思ったら、うん、ポルカ、やりたいだな、こいつって思っといてください！
Ah, this time too, since Polka gave all the names, if you think, 'Ah, that's so Polka,' then yeah, think, 'That's typical Polka, what a guy!'
で、ここが、ええと、グッズのご紹介で、え、フルセットを買うとですね、なんと数量限定特製チェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
And that concludes the merchandise introduction. If you buy the full set, surprise! A limited-quantity special cheki-style bromide card is included!
で、こちらね、説明が大変なんだ。ポルカ初の数量限定でございます。
And, this one's a bit complicated to explain. It's Polka's first-ever limited-quantity item.
まずですね、数量限定の方は、直筆メッセージと箔押しの複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついております。
First, the limited-quantity version comes with a hand-written message and foil-stamped duplicate signature cheki-style bromide card.
そして特製ボイスは、「今日は少し恥ずかしかったボイス」。でもこれは共通特製なので、ボイスはね、両方使えます。、え、あの、ついてきます。
And the special voice is 'A voice when I was a bit embarrassed today.' But since this is a common special, you get both voices—ah, they are included.
じゃあ、あの数量限定じゃない普通の誕生日記念フルセットには、普通、普通って言ったらあれだな、あの、すごいスペシャルな数量限定バージョンと
Now, as for the regular birthday full set (not limited quantity)—well, calling it 'regular' is a bit much, compared to the super special limited version,
スペシャル記念日フルセットは、えっと、直筆メッセージではないんですけれどもし、同じく箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついており、さらにこちらにも、え、少し恥ずかしかったボイスが
the special anniversary full set, um, doesn't have a handwritten message, but it also includes the foil-stamped duplicate signature cheki-style bromide card, and furthermore, it also includes the 'a bit embarrassed' voice,
ついておりますので、ええ、どちらもね、こうおっつけがたい内容となております！はい、ありがとうございます！
so, um, both options are neck-and-neck in terms of appeal! Yes, thank you!
そしてですね、あ！これ来ましたよ。最近流行りの、じゃない、最近流行りのやつね。
And then, oh! This has arrived. The currently trendy—no, the recently trendy one. Yes.
はい、こちら！じゃじゃーん！はい、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、去年から発売されているホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが
Yes, here! Ta-da! Yes, as a full set bonus for the talent premium goods, a card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game released since last year
1枚！1枚ついてきます。これ1カードに1枚だからね。
comes included—one card! It's one per card type, you see.
え、オフィシャル、失礼いたしました。カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみの対象になっております。
Ah, official—pardon me. The card is exclusively for those who purchased through the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典につくのはですね、推しをアピールできたりする、あの場所に置くやつだな。ヒーカード。推しホロメンカードでございます。
What comes as a bonus is, you know, the card you place where you can show off your oshi. The Oshi Holomember Card.
カードの詳細、遊び方についてはホームページをご覧ください。カードは日本語版のみとなっております。よろしくお願いします！
Please check the website for details on the cards and how to play. The cards are available in Japanese only. Thank you!
はい！いっぱい告知した！あー、ともじゃ！
Phew! That's a lot of announcements! Phew, Tomoja!
え、グッズ配信になるんだけどさ、もう今回ね、たくさん重大告知っていう部分があるんで、ポルカね、なかなか重大とか告知とか発表とか使わないんだけど、今回は使っていいかな！まずは1つ目、こちらを！どうぞ！
Um, it's about the merchandise stream, but this time, there are so many major announcements, and since Polka doesn't usually use words like 'major,' 'announcement,' or 'reveal,' I'll use it this time! First, the first one, here! Go!
特報
[Special Notice]
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
1stアルバム 発売決定！
1st Album Release Announced!
FILMY FUNNY
はあ！
Ha!
出ました！
It's here!
尾丸ポルカ 1stアルバム『Filmy Funny』
Omaru Polka's 1st album, "Filmy Funny,"
2025年1月31日リリース！
releasing on January 31, 2025!
ということで、きょーだい、やったー！
So hey siblings, yay!
こちら、なんとグッズ付き特装版あり！
This comes in a special goods-included edition!
え、今も見たと思いますが、
As you just saw,
全部直筆サインが付いた完全受注生産にて発売します！
and it will be released as a made-to-order product with handwritten signatures!
ということで、アルバムの現物自体はですね、この後予約開始がされてます。
So, pre-orders for the actual album will start right after this.
で、「いや、そんな待てねえよ、聴けねえよ」っていう方の為に、デジタルリリースもこの後の0時、というか24時から日付変わった瞬間にされます！
And for those of you saying, "I can't wait that long, I can't listen to it yet," a digital release will be out right at midnight, as the date changes!
でですね、先ほど言った直筆サインっていうのは、「え、限定盤だけなの？」と思うあなた。
And regarding the handwritten signatures I mentioned earlier, for those thinking, "Wait, is it only in the limited edition?"
いやいやいや、あの アナザージャケット、アナザージャケットというものが入りまして、
No, no, no—an alternate jacket is also included!
こちら、5絵柄があるんですけれども、その中のランダムで1枚、えー必ず、イラストはランダムなんですけど、1枚必ず直筆のサインがついてきます！
There are 5 illustrations, and one random one—though the illustration is random, one of them will definitely have a handwritten signature!
アルバム買った人！全員だよ！アルバム買った人！全員だよ！
Everyone who bought the album! Everyone! Everyone who bought the album! Everyone!
全員だよ！すごーい！
Everyone! That's amazing!
というわけで、アルバムの内容としては、本年度周年時にリリースされた「Forever Glow」ほか、新たに新曲を7曲収録しております！
So, the album contents include "Forever Glow," released during this year's anniversary, plus 7 brand-new songs!
お！
Oh!
そしてですね、えっと あの さらに、さらに、さらにこちらをご覧ください！
And furthermore... um, also, check this out!
絡まった糸は解けない 不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
The tangled threads won't untangle, the clumsy puppet dances today too.
みんなのために おどけたい
Wanting to act the fool for everyone's sake,
不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
the clumsy puppet dances today too.
本心忘れたフリをして
Pretending she's forgotten her true feelings.
み、見た？見ました？
D-Did you see it? Did you see that?
はーい、なんとこの後MVが出ます！新曲だー！
Yes! And an MV is coming out right after this! A new song!
まあ今回のね、あの、ライブのタイトル通り、ま、パペットなんですけれども、これがね、伏線回収だったとはみんな気づかなかっただろう。
Well, as the title of this live suggests, it's "Puppet," but I bet none of you realized that was foreshadowing.
もうそしてこの後、今からね、パペット、早速ここで歌うのですが、
And right after this, starting right now, we'll be singing "Puppet" right here.
えー、ちょっとドキドキしてます。あの、ちょっと見たと思うんだけど、cosMoPさんに作っていただきました。
Um, I'm kind of nervous. You probably saw it, but cosMo-P made it for us.
で、改めてね、まあこの曲も聴けるということで、アルバムやデジタルリリースもお手にとったり、えっと、お聴きください。
And so, once again, you can listen to this song, so please pick up the album or digital release and give it a listen.
ちょっとあの、ごめん、マジで緊張してるんだ。この曲かっこよすぎて。
Wait, sorry, I'm seriously so nervous. This song is just too cool.
というわけでですね、え、改めて、え、実はパペットを含めて、残りあと2曲になっております！
So with that said, to reiterate... actually, including "Puppet," there are only 2 songs left!
あ、いい声、いい声、いい声、いい声。よし、というわけで、残りあと2曲、最後まで盛り上がって、いくぞー！
Ah, nice voice, nice voice. Alright, so with 2 songs left, let's get hyped all the way to the end, let's go!
絡まった糸は解けない
The tangled threads won't untangle,
不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
the clumsy puppet dances today too.
みんなのために おどけたい
Wanting to act the fool for everyone's sake,
不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
the clumsy puppet dances today too.
本心忘れたフリをして
Pretending she's forgotten her true feelings,
行くぞ！イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！
Let's go! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊る
Spinning around and around, dancing and dancing,
私が舞えば皆笑顔になる
when I dance, everyone smiles.
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊る
Spinning around and around, dancing and dancing,
私もそれが嬉しい
I'm happy about that too.
でもでもころころころころ 巡り巡る
But round and round, rolling and rolling, turning and turning,
私の笑顔は本物なのかな？
is my smile really genuine?
ころころころころ 巡り巡る 悪い子な思考 隙間舞う
Rolling and rolling, turning and turning, naughty thoughts flutter through the gaps.
周りの期待に応えるための アン・ドゥ・トランスペット
A one-two transpose to answer everyone's expectations—
どうかどうか どうかお願い 見捨てないで嫌わないでね
please, please, please I beg you, don't abandon me, don't hate me!
本当は 愛情表現 ヘタクソなまま まあ回って
The truth is, my expression of love remains clumsy as I spin around,
転んで笑われて きっとこれが正解ね
falling and being laughed at—surely this correct world
世界は間違ってないよね 表情の支配！
isn't wrong, right? The domination of expression!
解錠宣言
Unlock declaration
ありのままままま
Just the way I am...
触って心の深い部分を
Touch the deepest parts of my heart,
そう言いかけて今日も鍵をかける
as I catch myself and lock it away once again.
あ、重かったよねゴメン 次は間違い無いようにするから
Ah, that was heavy, wasn't it? Sorry. Next time, I'll make sure not to make a mistake.
あ、重かったよねゴメン 謝ることしかできなくてごめん
Ah, that was heavy, wasn't it? Sorry. I'm sorry all I can do is apologize.
「ままままっ」それは本当の私じゃない！本当の私を見て！！
"Ma-ma-ma-ma" That's not the real me! Look at the real me!!
「ままままっ」それは本当の私だから！本当の私を見て！！
"Ma-ma-ma-ma" That is the real me! Look at the real me!!
錯乱 錯乱 取り乱した錯乱 結局正気になって結局
Confusion, confusion, frantic confusion... Becoming sane in the end,
どんな自分も愛してほしい 余すことなく全部愛してほしい
wanting you to love every version of me, wanting you to love all of me.
くるくるくるくる踊り踊れ 私が舞えば皆笑顔になる
Twirling and dancing around, when I dance, everyone smiles.
くるくるくるくる踊り踊れ 私もそれが嬉しい でも…
Twirling and dancing around, I'm happy about that too. But...
誰かの理想を演じるためのストップ・アンド・ゴー全部全部全部全部やるから
To play someone else's ideal, Stop and Go—I'll do all of it!
忘れないで 離れないで
Don't forget, don't leave me...
絡まった糸はほどけない 不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
The tangled threads won't untangle. The clumsy puppet dances today too,
みんなのために踊りたい 不器用なパペットは今日も踊る 本当の愛を探し求め
wanting to dance for everyone, searching for true love.
感情表現 バグったまままま 焦って突っ込んで落ち込んで感情表現 バグったまままま
Emotional expression still bugged... Panicking, rushing in, falling into despair—
愛情表現 ヘタクソなまままま 回って笑って笑われて
Affection expression still clumsy... Spinning, laughing, being laughed at—
きっとこれが正解ね世界！間違ってないよね感情の支配！
surely this is the correct world! This emotional domination isn't wrong, right?
解錠宣言 ありのままままま 触って心の深い部分を
Unlock declaration, just the way I am... Touch the deepest parts of my heart,
そう言いかけて今日も鍵をかける
as I catch myself and lock it away once again.
Welcome! あなたは選ばれしポルカサーカスのはじめてのお客様！
Welcome! You are the very first guests of the chosen Polka Circus!
やあやあ お待たせいたしました とてもハッピーな動物たち ユカイでかわいい魔界の子からエルフまで
Yay, yay! Sorry to keep you waiting. Very happy animals, from cute little denizens of the demon world to elves—
tv show じゃない ここだけのサーカス it's show time! なに見たい？どんなことでもしてあげる 私が座長その名も尾丸ポルカ
a circus unlike any other, it's show time! What do you want to see? I'll do anything for you. I'm the ringmaster, Omaru Polka!
ぜったい笑顔にさせちゃうぜ スマイル！それでは最後まで付き合ってもらうからな！準備はできてますか are you ready?
I'll definitely make you smile! Smile! Now then, you'll be sticking with me till the very end! Are you ready?
さあさあ近くにおいで きっと誰もが仰天 奇想天外なショーの始まりさ
Come on, closer! Surely everyone will be astounded. It's the start of an outlandish show!
グッと惹かれるでしょ？おっと！押さないでね それでは準備OKですか？
You're drawn right in, aren't you? Woah, don't push! So, is preparation OK?
愉快な動物たち 玉乗りピエロ
Merry animals, a ball-balancing clown—
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうでしょ
it's thrilling and nerve-wracking, isn't it?
真っ赤な輪くぐらせ 綱渡りして
Making them jump through bright red hoops, walking the tightrope—
ちょっとくらいのドジなんてご愛嬌よ
a little clumsiness is just part of the charm!
come on, light up! とっておきのライブ ボッーとしてないで
Come on, light up! A one-of-a-kind live show, don't zone out!
もっと！さあもっと！手を叩こう！
More! Come on, more! Let's clap our hands!
ほらほら着いておいで 目も回るようなサーカス きっとここだけだよ
Hey, keep up with me! A circus that'll make your head spin, definitely only here!
ホログラムみたい キラキラ 奇跡が踊る
Like a hologram, sparkling miracles dance.
いつかは世界中を虜にしちゃうぞ
Someday we'll captivate the entire world!
うーん 明日の演目はどうしようかな 屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議さ
Hmm, what should tomorrow's program be? A secret strategy meeting in the attic!
いっぱいの観客席が アッと驚くような とびきりのショーを見せましょう
Let's show the packed audience an astonishing, extraordinary show!
思い付いたらジッとしてられない 観客を引き連れて let's go!
When I think of something, I can't stay still. Dragging the audience along, let's go!
ねぇ あれがやりたい！ これもやりたい！ どうして時間て足りないの？
Hey, I want to do that! I want to do this too! Why is there never enough time?
さぁ みんなで手拍子 ペンライト！ めちゃくちゃ盛り上がっていってくれ 最後までお願いしまーす！
Now, everyone, clap your hands! Let's get super hyped up till the very end!
ポルカはネッツが好きです！みんなの好きな色はなんだろな？ ホログラム最高！
Polka loves netsu! I wonder what everyone's favorite color is? Hologram is the best!
不器用だって 絡まっちゃってばかりで
Clumsy and always getting tangled up,
少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど
Even on days when I feel a bit down,
見ててね 大丈夫！いつでも
Watch me! It's okay, always—
強気ヨシ！てらうなし
Stay strong! Have no shame!
顔を上げて 今日のステージが ほら
Lift your head, look, today's stage is...
ねぇ 待ってるのさ
Hey, waiting right here for you.
ポルカおるか？ ポルカおるか？ ポルカのコールでトイスでお願いします！
Is Polka here? Let's make some noise with the Polka call!
ポルカおるか？ ポルカおるよ！ こっちにもおるよ！
Is Polka here? Polka is here! Over here too!
ポルカおるか？ ポルカ歌うか こっちにもおるよ！ みんなのもとに おるよ！
Polka here? Will Polka sing? Over here too! Right by everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
強く強く願うんだ どんな夢だって
Wishing so strongly, no matter what dream,
きっときっと叶うはず
It'll surely, surely come true.
何も怖くない みんなの声は全部ちゃんと届いてるよ！
Nothing is scary! Everyone's voices have all reached me!
さあ 新しい次元 新しい舞台へ もっともっと突き進もう
Now, to a new dimension and stage, let's push further ahead!
まだまだ着いておいで 笑いころげちゃうサーカス 絶対ここだけだよ
Keep following me! A circus that'll make you laugh, right here only!
初めての仲間 景色に心も戻る
First companions, my heart returns to this scenery.
今にも世界中を
Even now, the whole world—
虜にしちゃうから目を離しちゃダメだぞ！
I'll captivate you, so don't take your eyes off me!
今年の誕生日も楽しい誕生日でした！
This year's birthday was such a fun birthday too!
あ、お別れ曲 ありがとうございました！
Ah, for our final song... Thank you very much!
今年もこの日がきたよ！！ みんなにいっぱいの愛を伝える日！！！！！
This day is here again!! A day to share all my love with everyone!!!!!